# RYAN HEITMANN, P.E.

SENIOR PROJECT MANAGER | ELECTRICAL ENGINEER

# PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Electrical Engineer with 9+ years Project Management in the Building Services Industry. Currently aiming to utilize my life-long interest in programming and pivot into Software Development with an interest in Back End Web Design. Fluent in C# with a strong familiarity of Python, and currently learning Javascript and Typescript.

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# WEB DEVELOPER | PURE TOUGH GYM | WELLINGTON, NZ June 2020 – July 2020

- Approached local gym owner and offered to redesign existing website
- Collaborated with owner and personal trainers regarding website content and layout
- Executed owner vision utilizing Wordpress and launched website at: http://www.puretough.co.nz

# PROJECT EXPERIENCE

# CHECK THE FRIDGE | SELF EMPLOYED | WELLINGTON, NZ July 2020 - Present

- Currently developing an ingredient-focused web application that will allow users to create meals and shopping lists based on ingredients owned and/or ingredients that need to be procured
- Back End is done in ASP.NET Core utilizing MVC and written in C#. Data is currently stored via SQL Server 2017 with near-term goal to utilize Entity
- Front End is utilizing Blazor pages with a near-term goal of utilizing Angular currently learning Javascript / Typescript and Angular.

# CS106A | STANFORD UNIVERSITY | PALO ALTO, CA April 2020 – May 2020

- Attended Stanford University's unique remote offering of CS106A 'Code in Place' available only during Covid-19 lockdown.
- Learned programming concepts and methodologies utilizing Python
- Submitted a simple 'Final Project' which can be found here: https://compedu.stanford.edu/codeinplace/public/projects/0846.html

#### **ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING EXPERIENCE**

#### SENIOR PROJECT MANAGER | ME ENGINEERS | DENVER, CO Dec 2018 – Aug 2019

- Project managed the power distribution, lighting, and fire alarm infrastructure for numerous \$100M+ USD projects
- Successfully delivered a high-quality product on-time while simultaneously working on 10+ projects ranging from professional stadia to residential apartments
- Mentored young engineers by promoting teamwork and providing direction on good design practices and client interaction

#### CONTACT

- RYAN.HEITMANN@GMAIL.COM
- © 021-113-4683
- 1/19 Byron Street Miramar, Wellington 6022
- in linkedin.com/in/rvan-heitmann
- github.com/RvHmann

## **S**KILLS

C#

SQL

**PYTHON** 

HTML

**CSS** 

JAVASCRIPT (BASIC)

TYPESCRIPT (BASIC)

UNITY (BASIC)

WORDPRESS

GIT

# **EDUCATION**

# B.S. ARCHITECTURAL ENGINEERING

KANSAS STATE UNIVERSITY MANHATTAN, KANSAS 2010

#### **CREDENTIALS**

LICENSED AND REGISTERED
PROFESSIONAL ELECTRICAL ENGINEER
STATE OF COLORADO

# RYAN HEITMANN, P.E.

SENIOR PROJECT MANAGER | ELECTRICAL ENGINEER

#### Projects of Note:

Daryl K Royal Memorial Stadium South Endzone Renovation – Austin, TX

Managed team in the successful delivery of construction documents for \$150M USD

Renovation and New Construction of South Endzone Structure for 100,119 seat

Collegiate American Football Stadium on time and within client's budget.

# ELECTRICAL PROJECT MANAGER | ME ENGINEERS | DENVER, CO Dec 2015 - Dec 2018

- Organized and ran meetings with architects, contractors, owners, code officials, and inspectors
- Co-managed and designed large-scale projects with high-value clients
- Served as on-site engineer for an American Football stadium: Issued in-field design directives, observed installation, and reviewed contractor change orders
- Passed the Professional Engineer (PE) Exam

#### Projects of Note:

Canvas Stadium at Colorado State University – Fort Collins, CO Assisted with power distribution and lighting design for new \$220M USD 41,000 seat Collegiate American Football Stadium. Acted as on-site engineer and commissioned sports lighting design to confirm compliance with NCAA Television Broadcast Criteria.

State Farm Arena Renovation - Atlanta, GA

Provided lead electrical design and project management for a challenging \$200M USD renovation of 16,600 seat NBA Basketball Arena and Concert Venue. Project was phased over multiple NBA seasons with a design team of over 15 subconsultants.

# PROJECT ELECTRICAL ENGINEER | ME ENGINEERS | DENVER, CO July 2014 - Dec 2015

- Provided power distribution, lighting, and fire alarm design while drafting in Revit
- Provided Construction Administration services by answering Contractor RFIs and writing Site Observation Reports

#### Projects of Note:

1776 Curtis Street - Denver, CO

Assisted senior electrical engineer with electrical design for 28 Story \$125M USD Multi-Use High Rise Building. Provided power distribution and lighting design, coordinated with sub-consultants, and provided construction administration.

#### ELECTRICAL DESIGNER | DBR ENGINEERING CONSULTANTS | HOUSTON, TX July 2010 - June 2014

- Provided power distribution, lighting, and fire alarm design while drafting in AutoCAD and Revit
- Successfully delivered quality construction documents on time while juggling 15+ projects at a time
- Worked as part of a multi-disciplinary team of seven engineers

# **Projects of Note:**

Project Champion - The Woodlands, TX

First substantial project while acting as lead electrical designer for twin Class A 13-story office buildings to house Exxon Mobil's Accounting Team. Attended meetings, coordinated with sub-consultants, and provided power distribution and lighting systems design.

# **HOBBIES & INTERESTS**

CYCLING (ROAD & MOUNTAIN)
BICYCLE BUILDING
COMPUTER PROGRAMMING
HIKING & TRAMPING
TRAVEL
COOKING
FOREIGN LANGUAGE (SPANISH)

#### **ENGINEERING SKILLS**

REVIT
AUTOCAD
BIM SOFTWARE
SKM POWER SUITE
AGI 32
MS OFFICE SUITE
BUILDING CODE (NEC, IBC)
ENERGY CODE (IEC, ASHRAE)
LEED CONSTRUCTION